grin.com 2019-08-02

# Privacy | GRIN | Publish your bachelor or master thesis, term paper, dissertation and essay for free

This privacy policy informs you about the nature, scope and purpose of the processing of personal data (hereinafter referred to as “data”) within our online offer of GRIN Verlag and its affiliated websites

  * grin.com
  * unterweisungen.de
  * diplomarbeiten24.de
  * hausarbeiten.de
  * referate24.de and
  * x-start.de

their functions and contents as well as external online presences, like e.g. our social media profiles (collectively referred to as “online offer”).

With regard to the terminology used, e.g. “Processing” or “Responsible”, we refer to the definitions in Article 4 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

We attach great importance to privacy, i. e. the protection of your personal data. Therefore, regardless of whether you are a new or long-standing author and / or customer, we ask you to take the time to read our privacy policy. If you have any questions about our policy as well as concerning the correction, blocking or deletion of data, please contact the contact address:

Open Publishing GmbH  
Nymphenburger Strasse 86  
80636 Munich  
Germany

Phone: 089/550559-0  
E-Mail: [info@grin.com](mailto:info@grin.com)  
Website: [www.openpublishing.com](https://www.openpublishing.com/)

The Open Publishing GmbH is represented by:  
Dr. Julius Mittenzwei and Christian Damke

 **Data Protection Officer**

Any data subject can also contact our data protection officer at any time with any questions or suggestions regarding data protection:

Open Publishing GmbH  
Data Protection Officer  
Nymphenburger Strasse 86  
80636 Munich  
Germany

“Personal data” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (hereinafter the “data subject”); a natural person is considered as identifiable, which can be identified directly or indirectly, in particular by means of assignment to an identifier such as a name, to an identification number, to location data, to an online identifier (e. g. cookie) or to one or more special features, that express the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of this natural person.

“Processing” means any process performed with or without the aid of automated procedures or any such process associated with personal data. The term goes far and includes virtually every handling of data.

“Responsible person” means the natural or legal person, public authority, body or body that decides, alone or in concert with others, on the purposes and means of processing personal data.

  * inventory data (e.g. names, adresses)
  * contact data (e.g. e-mail, phone numbers)
  * content data (e.g. written tests, photographs, videos)
  * usage data (e.g. visited websites, interests in content, access times)
  * meta data, communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses)

  * Providing the online offer of GRIN Verlag, its functions and contents.
  * Fulfillment of legal obligations or contracts.
  * Answering contact requests and communicating with users.
  * Security measures.
  * Audience measurement / Marketing.

You can trust us with your personal data. The data is encrypted and transmitted to us during the login or order process. We secure the online offer of GRIN Verlag and your data through technical and organizational measures against damage, destruction, alteration or unauthorized access by unauthorized persons. Despite regular checks, complete protection against all dangers is not possible.

If you register with us as author or customer, access to your author or customer account is only possible after entering your personal password. You should always treat your access data confidentially and close the browser window when you have finished communicating with us, especially if you share the computer with others.

We also take corporate privacy very seriously. Our employees and the service companies commissioned by us have been obliged by us to secrecy and to comply with data protection regulations.

## Relevant legal bases for the processing of data:

In accordance with Art. 13 GDPR, we inform you about the legal basis of our data processing. Unless the legal basis is stated in the privacy policy, the following applies:

  * The legal basis for obtaining consent is Article 6 (1) lit. a and Art. 7 GDPR,
  * the legal basis for the processing for the fulfillment of our services and the execution of contractual measures as well as the answer to inquiries is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR,
  * the legal basis for processing to fulfill our legal obligations is Art. 6 (1) lit. c GDPR,
  * and the legal basis for processing for the protection of our legitimate interests is Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR.
  * In the event that vital interests of the data subject or another natural person require the processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. d GDPR applies as legal basis.

We ask you to inform yourself regularly about the content of our privacy policy. We will adjust the privacy policy as soon as changes to our data processing require it. We will notify you as soon as the changes require your participation (e.g. consent) or other individual notification.

## Collaboration with processors and third parties

If, in the context of our processing, we disclose data to other persons and companies (contract processors or third parties), transmit them to them or otherwise grant access to the data, this will only be done on the basis of a legal permission (e.g. if a transmission of the data to third parties, as required by payment service providers, is pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR to fulfill the contract), if you have consented to a legal obligation or based on our legitimate interests (e.g. the use of agents, webhosters, etc.).

If we commission third parties to process data on the basis of a so-called “contract processing contract”, this is done on the basis of Art. 28 GDPR.

## Transfers to third countries

If we process data in a third country (i.e. outside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA)) or in the context of the use of third party services or disclosure or transmission of data to third parties, this will only be done if it is to fulfill our (pre) contractual obligations, on the basis of your consent, on the basis of a legal obligation or on the basis of our legitimate interests. Subject to legal or contractual permissions, we process or have the data processed in a third country only in the presence of the special conditions of Art. 44 et seq. GDPR. That the processing is e.g. on the basis of specific guarantees, such as the officially recognized level of data protection (e.g. for the US through the Privacy Shield) or compliance with officially recognized special contractual obligations (so-called “standard contractual clauses”).

You have the right to ask for confirmation as to whether the data in question is being processed and for information about this data as well as for further information and a copy of the data in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR.

You have according to Art. 16 GDPR the right to demand the completion of the data concerning you or the correction of the incorrect data concerning you.

In accordance with Art. 17 GDPR, you have the right to demand that the relevant data be deleted immediately or, alternatively, to require a restriction of the processing of data in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR.

You have the right to demand that the data relating to you, which you have provided to us, be obtained in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR and request their transmission to other persons responsible.

You have according to Art. 77 GDPR the right to file a complaint with the competent supervisory authority.

 **Withdrawal**

You have the right to grant consent in accordance with Art. 7 para. 3 GDPR with effect for the future.

 **Contradictory legal**

You can object to the future processing of your data in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR at any time. The objection may in particular be made against processing for direct marketing purposes.

## Cookies and right to object in direct mail

“Cookies” are small files that are stored on users’ computers. Different information can be stored within the cookies. A cookie is primarily used to store the information about a user (or the device on which the cookie is stored) during or after his visit to an online offer. Temporary cookies, or “session cookies” or “transient cookies”, are cookies that are deleted after a user leaves an online service and closes his browser. In such a cookie, e.g. the contents of a shopping cart are stored in an online store or a login jam. The term “permanent” or “persistent” refers to cookies that remain stored even after the browser has been closed. Thus, e.g. the login status will be saved if users visit it after several days. Likewise, in such a cookie the interests of the users can be stored, which are used for range measurement or marketing purposes. A “third-party cookie” refers to cookies that are offered by providers other than the person who manages the online offer (otherwise, if it is only their cookies, this is called “first-party cookies”).

We can use temporary and permanent cookies and clarify this in the context of this privacy policy.

We strive to provide you with the most personalized and user-friendly service possible. For this, and in order to make website improvements, we collect and store information about how you use our offer. We use cookies, small text files that your browser stores on your computer or mobile phone.

A cookie itself does not contain or collect any personal information about you or your internet usage. However, they are important, for example, for analyzing the behavior of guests on our website, or for showing personalized offers or for registering registered users for the duration of their visit. Cookies allow the website to “remember” you either for the duration of your current visit (“session cookie”) or for multiple visits (“persistent cookie”). First and foremost, they should allow you to use our website more efficiently and activate certain functions on the website.

 **How can you control the receipt of cookies?**

Most web browsers accept cookies automatically. You can prevent cookies from being stored on your computer or mobile phone by setting your browser to not accept cookies. For detailed instructions on how to change your cookie settings, see the “Help” section of your browser. You can also at any time delete the cookies that are already stored on your device. Helpful information can be found on the information page [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org//).

If you decide to generally not accept cookies, you can of course visit our website anyway. However, it may happen that you will not be able to use all the features and services or that certain content we offer will be unavailable.

A general contradiction against the use of the cookies used for the purpose of online marketing can be explained in a variety of services, in particular in the case of tracking, via the US side [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or the EU page [www.youronlinechoices.com/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

The data processed by us are deleted or limited in their processing in accordance with the Articles 17 and 18 GDPR. Unless explicitly stated in this privacy policy, the data stored by us are deleted as soon as they are no longer required for their purpose and the deletion does not conflict with any statutory storage requirements. Unless the data is deleted because it is required for other and legitimate purposes, its processing will be restricted. That is, the data is blocked and not processed for other purposes. This applies, for example for data that must be kept for commercial or tax reasons.

According to legal requirements in Germany, the storage takes place in particular for 6 years pursuant to § 257 paragraph 1 HGB (trading books, inventories, opening balance sheets, annual accounts, trade letters, accounting documents, etc.) and for 10 years in accordance with § 147 Abs. 1 AO (books, records, Management reports, accounting documents, trade and business letters, documents relevant to taxation, etc.).

## Business-related processing

In addition, we process the following data from our customers, prospects and business partners for the purpose of providing contractual services, service and customer care, marketing, advertising and market research:

  * Contract data (e.g. contract, period of validity, customer category).
  * Payment data (e.g. bank details, payment history).

The hosting services we use are for the purpose of providing the following services: infrastructure and platform services, computing capacity, storage and database services, security and technical maintenance services we use to operate this online service.

Here we, or our hosting provider, process inventory data, contact data, content data, contract data, usage data, meta and communication data of customers, interested parties and visitors to this online offer on the basis of our legitimate interests in an efficient and secure provision of this online offer acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR in conjunction with Art. 28 GDPR (conclusion of contract processing contract).

## Collection of access data and log files

We, or our hosting provider, collect on the basis of our legitimate interests within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR data on every access to the server on which this service is located (so-called server log files). The access data includes the name of the retrieved web page, file, date and time of retrieval, amount of data transferred, message about successful retrieval, browser type and version, the user’s operating system, referrer URL (the previously visited page), IP address and the requesting provider.

Logfile information is stored for security purposes (for example, to investigate abusive or fraudulent activities) for a maximum of 7 days and then deleted. Data whose further retention is required for evidential purposes shall be exempted from the cancellation until final clarification of the incident.

## Order processing in the online shop and customer account

We process the data of our customers as part of the ordering process in our online shop to allow them to select and order the selected products and services, as well as their payment and delivery, or execution.

The processed data includes inventory data, communication data, contract data, payment data and the persons affected by the processing include our authors, customers, prospects and other business partners. Processing is for the purpose of providing contractual services in the context of the operation of an online shop, billing, delivery and customer service. Here we use session cookies for the storage of the shopping cart contents and permanent cookies for the storage of the login status.

Processing is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b (execution of order transactions) and c (legally required archiving) GDPR. The information marked as required for the establishment and fulfillment of the contract is required. We disclose the data to third parties only in the context of extradition, payment or in the context of legal permissions and obligations to legal advisors and authorities. The data will be processed in third countries only if necessary for the fulfillment of the contract (for example, on customer’s request upon delivery or payment).

Users can optionally create a user account in which they can in particular view their orders. As part of the registration, the necessary mandatory information will be communicated to the users. The user accounts are not public and cannot be indexed by search engines. If users have terminated their user account, their data regarding the user account will be deleted, subject to their retention is necessary for commercial or tax law reasons according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR.

Information in the customer account remains until its deletion with subsequent archiving in case of a legal obligation. It is the responsibility of the users to secure their data upon termination before the end of the contract.

As part of the registration and re-registration and use of our online services, we store the IP address and the time of the respective user action. The storage is based on our legitimate interests, as well as the user’s protection against misuse and other unauthorized use. A transfer of these data to third parties does not take place, unless it is necessary for the prosecution of our claims or there is a legal obligation in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR.

The deletion takes place after expiry of legal warranty and comparable obligations, the necessity of keeping the data is checked every three years; in the case of legal archiving obligations, the deletion takes place after its expiration (end of commercial law (6 years) and tax law (10 years) retention obligation).

 **Payment via PayPal:**

If you pay for services with Paypal (PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg), data on the purchase will be forwarded to Paypal. The privacy policy of Paypal can be found here: <https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>.

 **Payment via debit or credit card:**

For the processing of credit card and direct debit payments, we use the service provider PayOne (BS PAYONE GmbH, Lyoner Strasse 9, 60528 Frankfurt / Main, Germany). PayOne provides an interface for initiating payment transactions and submitting data to the PayOne platform. Payments are made in a separate area (iframes) by PayOne on our website. Our systems are therefore not in direct contact with the buyer’s card data.

The privacy policy of PayOne can be found here: [https://www.payone.com/en/privacy/.](https://www.payone.com/en/privacy/)  
For the data processing of the payment processing services, they are “responsible” themselves.

## Provision of contractual services

We process inventory data (e.g., names and addresses as well as user and author contact information), contract data (e.g., services used, contact names, billing information) for the purpose of fulfilling our contractual obligations and services in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit b. GDPR. The entries marked as obligatory in online forms are required for the conclusion of the contract.

As part of the use of our online services, we store the IP address and the time of each user action. The storage is based on our legitimate interests, as well as the interests of users against abuse and other unauthorized use. A transfer of these data to third parties does not take place, unless it is necessary for the prosecution of our claims or there is a legal obligation in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR.

We process usage data (e.g. the visited web pages of our online offering or interest in our products) and content data (e.g. entries in the contact form or user profile) for advertising purposes in a user profile to inform the user e.g. about product instructions based on their previously used services.

The deletion of the data takes place after expiration of legal warranty and comparable obligations, the necessity of the storage of the data is checked every three years; in the case of legal archiving obligations, the deletion takes place after its expiration. Information in the customer’s account remains until it is deleted.

## Administration, financial accounting, office organization, contact management

We process data in the context of administrative tasks and organization of our business, financial accounting and compliance with legal obligations, such as archiving. We process the same data that we process in the course of rendering our contractual services. The processing principles are Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c. GDPR, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR. The processing affects customers, prospects, business partners and website visitors. The purpose and interest in processing lies in administration, financial accounting, office organization and data archiving, which are tasks that serve to maintain our business, perform our duties and provide our services. The deletion of the data in terms of contractual performance and contractual communication corresponds to the information provided in these processing activities.

We disclose or transmit data to the financial administration, consultants, such as tax accountants or auditors, and other fee agents and payment service providers.

Furthermore, based on our business interests, we store information about suppliers, promoters and other business partners, e.g. for later contact. We generally store this, mostly company-related data permanently.

## Business analysis and market research

In order to operate our business economically, to be able to recognize market trends and customer and user requirements, we analyze the data we have on business transactions, contracts, inquiries, etc. We process stock data, communication data, contract data, payment data, usage data, metadata on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR, whereby the persons affected include customers, prospects, business partners, visitors and users of the online offer.

The analyses are carried out for the purpose of business analysis, marketing and market research. In doing so, we can display the profiles of the registered users with indications e.g. to consider their purchase transactions. The analyses serve to increase the user-friendliness, the optimization of our offer and the business economics. The analyses are for us alone and will not be disclosed externally unless they are anonymous, aggregated value analyses.

If these analyses or profiles are personal, they will be deleted or anonymized upon termination of the users, otherwise after two years from the conclusion of the contract. Incidentally, the overall business analyzes and general trend provisions are created anonymously if possible.

## Privacy policy in the application process and Talent Pool

We process the applicant data only for the purpose and in the context of the application process in accordance with all legal requirements. The processing of the applicant data takes place in order to fulfill our (pre-) contractual obligations in the context of the application process within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b. GDPR Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR if the data processing e.g. is required for us in the context of legal proceedings (in Germany, § 26 BDSG applies additionally).

The application process requires applicants to provide us with the applicant data. The necessary applicant data are, as far as we offer an online form, marked or otherwise result from the job descriptions and basically include the information on the person, postal and contact addresses and the application documents, such as cover letter, CV and the certificates. In addition, applicants can voluntarily provide us with additional information.

By submitting the application to us, the applicants agree to the processing of their data for the purposes of the application process in accordance with the nature and scope set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Insofar as special categories of personal data within the meaning of Art. 9 (1) GDPR are voluntarily communicated within the framework of the application procedure, their processing is additionally carried out in accordance with Art. 9 (2) lit. b GDPR (e.g., health information such as disability or ethnic origin). Insofar as special categories of personal data within the meaning of Art. 9 (1) GDPR are requested from applicants in the context of the application procedure, their processing is additionally carried out in accordance with Art. 9 para. 2 lit. a GDPR (for example health data, if necessary for the profession).

If provided, applicants can submit their applications to us via an online form on our website. The data will be encrypted and transmitted to us according to the state of the art.

Furthermore, applicants can send us their applications via e-mail. However, please note that e-mails are generally not sent in encrypted form and that applicants themselves must provide encryption. We can therefore take no responsibility for the transmission of the application between the sender and the reception on our server and therefore recommend rather to use an online form or the postal delivery. Instead of applying via the online form and e-mail, applicants still have the opportunity to send us the application by post.

The data provided by the applicants may be further processed by us in the event of a successful application for employment purposes. Otherwise, if the application for a job offer is not successful, the applicants’ data will be deleted. Applicants’ data will also be deleted if an application is withdrawn, which the applicants are entitled to at any time.

The deletion takes place, subject to a legitimate revocation of the candidate, after the expiration of a period of six months, so that we can answer any follow-up questions to the application and meet our obligations under the Equal Treatment Act. Invoices for any reimbursement of travel expenses are archived in accordance with the tax regulations.

 **Talent Pool**

As part of the application, we offer applicants the opportunity to be in our “Talent Pool” for a period of two years on the basis of a consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b. and Art. 7 GDPR.

The application documents in the Talent Pool are processed solely as part of future job advertisements and job search and will be destroyed at the latest after the deadline. Candidates are informed that their consent to be admitted to the talent pool is voluntary, has no influence on the current application process and that they can revoke this consent at any time in the future and declare an objection within the meaning of Art. 21 GDPR.

We are, based on our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in the economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. GDPR), participants in the Affiliate Program of Amazon EU (Amazon Europe Core S.à.rl, the Amazon EU S.à.rl, Amazon Services Europe S.à.rl and Amazon Media EU S.à.rl, all four located at 5, Rue Plaetis, L-2338 Luxembourg), which was designed to provide a medium for websites, by means of which advertising costs can be earned through the placement of advertisements and links to Amazon.de (so-called affiliate system). Amazon uses cookies to track the origin of orders. Among other things, Amazon may recognize that you have clicked the affiliate link on this site and subsequently purchased a product from Amazon.

For more information about Amazon’s data usage and opt-out options, please visit the company’s privacy policy: <https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496>.

Users can optionally create a user account. As part of the registration, the necessary mandatory information is communicated to the users. The data entered during registration will be used for the purpose of using the offer. Users may be informed by e-mail about offer or registration-related information, such as changes in the scope of the offer or technical circumstances. If users have terminated their user account, their data regarding the user account will be deleted, subject to their retention is necessary for commercial or tax law reasons according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR. It is the responsibility of the users to secure their data upon termination before the end of the contract. We are entitled to irretrievably delete all user data stored during the term of the contract.

In the context of the use of our registration and registration functions as well as the use of the user account, we store the IP address and the time of the respective user action. The storage is based on our legitimate interests, as well as the user’s protection against misuse and other unauthorized use. A transfer of these data to third parties does not take place, unless it is necessary for the prosecution of our claims or there is a legal obligation in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR. The IP addresses will be anonymized or deleted after 7 days at the latest.

When contacting us (for example, by contact form, e-mail, telephone or via social media) the information of the user to process the contact request is processed in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR. User information can be stored in a Customer Relationship Management System (“CRM System”) or comparable request organization.

We delete the requests, if they are no longer required. We check the necessity every two years; Furthermore, the legal archiving obligations apply.

To manage the e-mails to our contact [info@grin.com](mailto:info@grin.com), we use Freshdesk, a service of Freshworks, Inc., 1250 Bayhill Drive, Suite 315, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA as a Help Center solution. When you submit a request, certain personal information in connection with your support request, such as your e-mail address, will be collected and stored by Freshdesk. Depending on the nature of your request, further data such as your first and last name or phone number is collected and stored. These data are hosted by Freshdesk in a data center in Frankfurt am Main. However, because Freshdesk uses third-party applications, your data may occasionally be processed and stored outside the EU. However, we have entered into contractual agreements with Freshworks, Inc. to ensure sufficient levels of data protection (EU standard contract clauses).

There will be no reconciliation of the data collected with data collected from other components of our website.

For more information about Freshworks’ data usage, please read the company’s privacy policy: <https://www.freshworks.com/privacy/gdpr/>.

If users leave comments or other contributions, their IP addresses may, based on our legitimate interests within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR, be stored for 7 days. This is for our own safety, if someone leaves illegal content in comments and contributions (insults, prohibited political propaganda, etc.). In this case, we ourselves can be prosecuted for the comment or post and are therefore interested in the identity of the author.

Furthermore, we reserve the right, in accordance with our legitimate interests according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR, to process the information of users for the purpose of spam detection.

## VG Word / Scalable Central Measurement Method

We use the “Scalable Central Measurement Method” (SZM) of INFOnline GmbH (INFOnline GmbH, Brühler Str. 9, D-53119 Bonn) for the determination of statistical parameters for determining the copy probability of texts. Anonymous measurements are taken. Alternatively, traffic metering uses a session cookie or signature created from various automatically transmitted information from your browser to recognize computer systems. IP addresses are only processed in anonymous form. The procedure was developed in compliance with data protection. The only goal of the procedure is to determine the copy probability of individual texts. At no time individual users are identified. Your identity always remains protected. You will not receive advertising through the system.

Many of our pages are provided with JavaScript calls, through which we report the access to the “Verwertungsgesellschaft Wort” (VG Wort). We allow our authors to participate in the distributions of the VG Wort, which complies with the legal remuneration for the use of copyrighted works in accordance with Art. § 53 UrhG.

Usage data and metadata of the users are processed here, whereby the IP addresses are being shortened and the measuring methods are pseudonymous. The shortened IP address is stored for a maximum of 60 days. The usage data in connection with a pseudonymous assignment value (“Identifier”) are stored for a maximum of 6 months.

Users are also provided with an opt-out in order to disagree with the collection for the aforementioned purposes: [https://optout.ioam.de](https://optout.ioam.de/). Further information can be found in the data protection statement of INFOnline <https://www.infonline.de/datenschutz/benutzer>.

With the following information we inform you about the contents of our newsletter as well as the registration, dispatch and statistical evaluation procedures as well as your right of objection. By subscribing to our newsletter, you agree to the receipt and the procedures described.

Content of the newsletter: We send newsletters, e-mails and other electronic notifications with advertising information (hereinafter “newsletter”) only with the consent of the recipient or a legal permission. Insofar as the contents of a newsletter are concretely described, they are authoritative for the consent of the users. Incidentally, our newsletter contains information about our services and us.

Double opt-in and logging: Registration for our newsletter is done in a so-called double-opt-in procedure. That means after registration, you will receive an e-mail asking you to confirm your registration. This confirmation is necessary so that nobody can register with external e-mail addresses. The registration for the newsletter will be logged in order to prove the registration process according to the legal requirements. This includes the storage of the login and the confirmation time, as well as the IP address. Likewise, changes to your data stored with the shipping service provider will be logged.

Login details: To subscribe to the newsletter, it is sufficient to provide your e-mail address. Optionally, we ask you to provide a name in order to be able to address you personally in the newsletter.

Germany: The newsletter is sent and the related performance measurement is done

  * based on the consent of the recipients acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a, Art. 7 GDPR in connection with § 7 Abs. 2 Nr. 3 UWG or on the basis of the legal permission according to Art. § 7 Abs. 3 UWG.
  * or based on our legitimate interests Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR or on the basis of the legal permission according to para. 7 Abs. 3 UWG. We are interested in promoting the academic exchange between our users, information on new editions and new scientific developments as well as new offerings in the dissemination of academic publications and on direct marketing, i.e. the contact with customers and potential authors.

The logging of the registration process is based on our legitimate interests in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. Our interest lies in the use of a user-friendly and secure newsletter system, which serves both our business interests and the expectations of the users and also allows us to prove our consent.

 **Termination / Revocation**

You can terminate the receipt of our newsletter at any time, i.e. revoke your consent. A link to cancel the newsletter can be found at the end of each newsletter. We may save the submitted e-mail addresses for up to three years, based on our legitimate interests, before we delete them to provide prior consent. The processing of this data is limited to the purpose of a possible defense against claims. An individual request for cancellation is possible at any time, provided that at the same time the former existence of a consent is confirmed.

 **Newsletter – shipping service provider**

The newsletters will be sent by MailChimp, a mail-order service provider of Rocket Science Group, LLC, 675 Ponce De Leon Ave # 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308, USA. The privacy policy of the shipping service provider can be viewed here: <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>. The Rocket Science Group LLC is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European data protection standards: [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TO6hAAG&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TO6hAAG&status=Active).

The shipping service provider is based on our legitimate interests acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR and a contract processing agreement acc. Art. 28 (3) sentence 1 GDPR.

The shipping service provider may use the data of the recipients in pseudonymous form, i.e. without assignment to a user, to optimize or improve their own services, e.g. for the technical optimization of shipping and the presentation of newsletters or for statistical purposes. However, the shipping service provider does not use the data of our newsletter recipients to address them themselves or to pass the data on to third parties.

 **Newsletter – Success Measurement**

The newsletters contain a so-called “web-beacon”, i.e. a pixel-sized file that is retrieved from the server when opening the newsletter from our server, or if we use a shipping service provider whose server is called. This call will initially collect technical information, such as information about the browser and your system, as well as your IP address and time of retrieval.

This information is used to improve the technical performance of services based on their specifications or audience and their reading habits, based on their locations (which can be determined using the IP address) or access times. Statistical surveys also include determining if the newsletters will be opened, when they will be opened and which links will be clicked. For technical reasons, this information can be assigned to the individual newsletter recipients. However, it is neither our goal nor, if used, that of the shipping service provider to observe individual users. The evaluations rather serve us to recognize the reading habits of our users and to adapt our content to them or to send different content according to the interests of our users.

## Website tests with Optimizely

The Optimizely web analytics service by Optimizely Inc. (631 Howard St. Suite 100, San Francisco, CA 94105) is incorporated on this website. This is used for A / B and multivariate tests. Optimizely uses cookies to recognize a site visitor and to analyze the use of the website.

The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to and stored by an Optimizely server in the USA. However, as IP anonymization is activated on this website, your IP address will be shortened by Optimizely beforehand. This applies within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to an Optimizely server in the USA and shortened there. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

You can disable Optimizely tracking at any time by following the instructions at <http://www.optimizely.com/opt_out>.

Based on our legitimate interests (i.e., interest in the analysis, optimization, and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. GDPR), Google Analytics uses a web analytics service provided by Google LLC (“Google”). Google uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about the use of the online offer by the users are usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. To learn more about how Google uses data when using partners’ websites and apps, visit: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites?hl=en>.

Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate the use of our online offer by users, to compile reports on the activities within this online offer and to provide us with further services related to the use of this online offer and the internet usage. In this case, pseudonymous usage profiles of the users can be created from the processed data.

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation: [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active).

We only use Google Analytics with activated IP anonymization. This means that the IP address of the users will be shortened by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there.

The IP address submitted by the user’s browser will not be merged with other data provided by Google. Users can prevent the storage of cookies by setting their browser software accordingly; Users may also prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to its use of the online offer and the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

For more information about Google’s data usage, hiring and disparaging options, please read Google’s Privacy Policy (<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en>) and the settings for the display of advertising by Google (<https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>).

The personal data of users will be deleted or anonymized after 14 months.

## Google Re/Marketing Services

On the basis of our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. GDPR) we use the marketing and remarketing services (“Google Marketing Services “), LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, (“Google”).

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)).

Google Marketing Services allows us to better target advertisements for and on our website so that we only present ads to users that potentially match their interests. If a user e.g. is being shown ads for products he’s been interested in on other websites, this is called remarketing. For these purposes, when Google and our other websites accessing Google Marketing Services are directly accessed by Google, a code will be executed by Google and so-called (re) marketing tags (invisible graphics or code, also called “Web Beacons “) are being incorporated into the website. With their help, the user is provided with an individual cookie, i.e. a small file is saved (instead of cookies, comparable technologies can also be used). The cookies can be set by different domains, including google.com, doubleclick.net, invitemedia.com, admeld.com, googlesyndication.com or googleadservices.com. In this file is noted which web pages the user visited, in what content he is interested and what offers he has clicked, as well as technical information about the browser and operating system, referring web pages, visiting time and other information on the use of the online offer. The IP address of the users is also recorded, whereby in the context of Google Analytics we announce that the IP address is shortened within member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area and is only in exceptional cases being transmitted to one Google server in the US and shortened there. The IP address will not be merged with data of the user within other offers from Google. The above information may also be linked by Google with such information from other sources. If the user then visits other websites, ads tailored to him can be displayed according to his interests.

The data of the users are pseudonymously processed in the context of the Google marketing services. I.e. Google stores and processes e.g. not the name or e-mail address of the users, but processes the relevant data cookie-related within pseudonymous user profiles. I.e. from the perspective of Google, the ads are not managed and displayed to a specifically identified person, but to the cookie owner, regardless of who that cookie owner is. This does not apply if a user has explicitly allowed Google to process the data without this pseudonymization. The information collected about users through Google Marketing Services is transmitted to Google and stored on Google’s servers in the United States.

Among the Google marketing services we use is the online advertising program “Google AdWords”. In the case of Google AdWords, each advertiser receives a different “conversion cookie”. Cookies cannot be tracked through AdWords advertisers’ websites. The information collected through the cookie is used to generate conversion statistics for AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. Advertisers will see the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag page. However, they do not receive information that personally identifies users.

We can incorporate third-party ads based on the Google AdSense marketing service. AdSense uses cookies that enable Google and its affiliate sites to serve ads based on users’ visits to this site or other sites on the Internet.

In addition, we may use the “Google Tag Manager” to integrate and manage the Google Analytics and Marketing Services on our website.

For more information about Google’s data usage for marketing, see the overview page: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads?hl=en>, Google’s Privacy Policy is available at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy?hl=en>.

If you wish to object the interest-based advertising through Google Marketing Services, you can take advantage of Google’s setting and opt-out options: <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences>.

## Facebook-Pixels, Custom Audiences and Facebook Conversion

Within our online offer the so-called “Facebook pixel” of the social network Facebook, by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA, or, if you are located in the EU, Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, Dublin 2, Ireland (“Facebook”) is used due to our legitimate interests in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer and for these purposes.

Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active)).

With the help of the Facebook pixel, it is on the one hand possible for Facebook to determine the visitors to our online offer as a target group for the display of advertisements (so-called “Facebook ads”). Accordingly, we use the Facebook Pixel to display the Facebook Ads we operate only to those Facebook users who have shown an interest in our online offer or who show certain features (e.g. interests in certain topics or products which are determined on the basis of visited websites), which we transmit to Facebook (so-called “Custom Audiences”). With the help of the Facebook pixel, we also want to make sure that our Facebook ads are in line with the potential interest of users and are not annoying. With the help of the Facebook pixel we can also understand the effectiveness of the Facebook ads for statistical and market research purposes, in which we see whether users were redirected to our website after clicking on a Facebook ad (so-called “conversion”).

The processing of the data by Facebook is part of Facebook’s data usage policy. Accordingly, general notes on how to display Facebook Ads, in Facebook’s Data Usage Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>. For specific information and details about the Facebook Pixel and how it works, visit the help section of Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/business/help/651294705016616>.

You may object to the capture by the Facebook Pixel and use of your data to display Facebook Ads. To set which types of ads you see within Facebook, you can go to the page set up by Facebook and follow the instructions for the usage-based advertising settings: <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads>. The settings are platform independent, i.e. they are adopted for all devices, such as desktop computers or mobile devices.

You can also object to the use of cookies for distance measurement and promotional purposes via the deactivation page of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/>) and in addition the US website (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices>) or the European website (<http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices/>).

## Online presence in social media

We maintain online presence within social networks and platforms in order to communicate with customers, prospects and users active there and to inform them about our services. When calling the respective networks and platforms, the terms and conditions and the data processing guidelines apply to their respective operators.

Unless otherwise stated in our Privacy Policy, we process users’ data as long as they communicate with us within social networks and platforms, e.g. write posts on our online presence or send us messages.

## Usage Based Advertising - Online Behavioral Advertising (OBA)

## Usage Based Advertising - Measurement Procedure SZMnG by INFOnline GmbH

Our web pages use the measurement procedure (“SZMnG”) provided by INFOnline GmbH ([https://www.INFOnline.de](https://www.infonline.de/en/)) to measure statistical parameters relating to the use of our sites. The reason for collecting these user metrics is to statistically measure the number of visits to our websites, the number of visitors and their surfing behaviour using a standardised procedure to allow values to be collected that are comparable across the market.

For all sites that are members of the Informationsgemeinschaft zur Feststellung der Verbreitung von Werbeträgern e.V. [German Audit Bureau of Circulation] ([IVW – http://www.ivw.eu](https://www.ivw.eu/englische-version)) or that participate in online research carried out by the Arbeitsgemeinschaft Online-Forschung e.V. [German Online Research Working Group] ([AGOF – http://www.agof.de](https://www.agof.de/en/)), the user metrics will be processed further on a regular basis by the AGOF and the Working Group for Media Analysis ([agma – http://www.agma-mmc.de](https://www.agma-mmc.de/)) and will be published under the performance indicator “Unique User” as well as by the IVW with the performance indicators “Page Impression” and “Visits”. This reach and statistics can be accessed on their respective web pages.

 **1\. Legal Basis for Processing**  
The measurement by INFOnline GmbH using the SZMnG measurement procedure is carried out upon legitimate interest, under Art. 6 Para.1 lit. f) of the GDPR.  
The purpose of processing personal data is to gain statistics and to create user categories. The statistics are used to understand and substantiate the use of our sites. The user categories form the basis for an interest-oriented alignment of advertising material and advertising measures. A usage measurement which guarantees comparability with competitors in the market is essential for the marketing of this web page. Our legitimate interest stems from the economic usability of our findings that we get from the statistics, user categories and the market value of our web pages, as well as the direct comparison with third-party web pages, which can be determined from the statistics.  
In addition, we have a legitimate interest in making the pseudonymised data of INFOnline, AGOF and IVW available for the purposes of market research (AGOF, agma) and for statistical purposes (INFOnline, IVW). Furthermore, we have a legitimate interest in providing INFOnline’s pseudonymised data for the further development and provision of interest-oriented advertising material.

 **2\. Types of Data**  
INFOnline GmbH collects the following data which, according to EU-GDPR, can be linked to a particular person:

  * IP address: On the Internet, each device requires a unique address to transmit information: the IP address. Because of how the Internet functions, it is technically necessary for the IP address to be stored, at least for a short period. IP addresses are truncated to 1 byte before any processing. Further processing is only performed on anonymised IP addresses. No IP addresses that have not been truncated are saved or processed.
  * A randomly generated Client ID: To allow computer systems to be recognised, the further processing uses either a third-party cookie, a first-party cookie, a local storage object or a signature that is compiled from diverse information from your browser that is transmitted automatically. This identification is explicit for a browser, as long as the cookie or local storage object is not deleted. It is possible to measure the data and to subsequently assign it to the respective client identifier by accessing other websites that also use the measuring method (“SZMnG”) of INFOnline GmbH.  
The validity of the cookie is restricted to a maximum of 1 year.

 **3\. Data Use**  
INFOnline GmbH’s measurement process, which is posted on this web page, determines usage data. This is done to collect the performance indicators of page impressions, visits and clients, and to provide additional performance indicators (e.g. qualified clients). In addition, the measured data is used as follows:

  * Geolocalisation (web page access being linked to the access location) is performed exclusively on the basis of the anonymised IP addresses and only to the geographical level of federal state/region. The collected geographical information cannot, under any circumstances, be used to determine a user’s specific place of residence.
  * The usage data from a technical client (e.g. from a device’s browser) are amalgamated from all web pages and saved in a database. This information is technically evaluated for age and gender and handed over to the AGOF service providers for further processing. In the course of the AGOF study, random samples for social characteristics are taken for technical evaluation, which are organised into the following categories: Age, Gender, Nationality, Occupation, Marital Status, General Household Information, Household Income, Place of Residence, Internet Use, Online Interests, Place of Use, Type of User.

 **4\. Data Storage Time**  
The full IP address will not be saved by INFOnline GmbH. The truncated IP address will be saved for a maximum of 60 days. The usage data in connection with the unique identifier is saved for a maximum of 6 months.

 **5\. Data Disclosure**  
Neither the IP address nor the truncated IP address will be disclosed. The data with client IDs will be disclosed to the following AGOF service providers for the creation of the AGOF study:

  * Kantar Deutschland GmbH ([https://www.tns-infratest.com/](https://www.kantartns.de/))
  * Ankordata GmbH & Co. KG ([http://www.ankordata.de/homepage/](https://www.ankordata.de/homepage/))
  * Interrogare GmbH ([https://www.interrogare.de/](https://www.interrogare.de/en/))

 **6\. Rights of the Data Subject**  
The data subject has the following rights:

  * Right of access (Art.15 GDPR)
  * Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)
  * Right to object(Art. 21 GDPR)
  * Right to erasure (Art. 17 GDPR)
  * Right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR)
  * Right to data portability (Art.20 GDPR)

For inquiries related to this, please consult privacy@openpublishing.com. Please note: For questions such as these, we must ensure that the question actually involves the data subject.

 **Right to Object**  
If you would rather not take part in the measurement, you can opt out via the following link: [https://optout.ioam.de](https://optout.ioam.de/) In order to guarantee exclusion from the measurement, it is a technical requirement to set a cookie. Should you wish to delete your browser’s cookies, you must go through the opt-out process using the above-mentioned link.

The data subject has the right to submit a complaint to a data protection authority.

Further information on data protection in the measurement procedure can be found on the website of INFOnline GmbH (the company that operates the measurement procedure) ([https://www.infonline.de](https://www.infonline.de/en/)), AGOF’s web page concerning data protection ([http://www.agof.de/datenschutz](http://www.agof.de/en/datenschutz-allgemein/)) and the IVW’s data protection web page ([http://www.ivw.eu](https://www.ivw.eu/englische-version)).

## Integration of services and contents of third parties

Based on our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. GDPR), we make use of content or services offered by third-party providers in order to provide their content and services, such as include videos or fonts (collectively referred to as “content”).

This always presupposes that the third-party providers of this content perceive the IP address of the users, since they could not send the content to their browser without the IP address. The IP address is therefore required for the presentation of this content. We endeavor to use only content whose respective providers use the IP address solely for the delivery of the content. Third parties may also use so-called pixel tags (invisible graphics, also referred to as “web beacons”) for statistical or marketing purposes. The “pixel tags” can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on the pages of this website. The pseudonymous information may also be stored in cookies on the user’s device and may include, but is not limited to, technical information about the browser and operating system, referring web pages, visit time, and other information regarding the use of our online offer.

We embed the videos on the YouTube platform of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>, Opt-Out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

We use the so-called “extended privacy mode” of the provider YouTube to embed videos. At the same time, a cookie is only saved on your computer when the video is played. According to YouTube, however, no personal cookie information is stored for playing embedded videos with enhanced privacy. For more information about YouTube’s official privacy policy, please visit: <http://www.youtube.com/t/privacy_at_youtube>

If you want to be sure that no data is being saved on YouTube, do not click on the embedded videos.

We include maps from the Google Maps service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. The processed data may include, in particular, users’ IP addresses and location data, but these are not collected without their consent (usually as part of the settings of their mobile devices). The data can be processed in the USA. Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>, Opt-Out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

## Use of Facebook social plugins

Based on our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) f. GDPR) we use social plugins (“plugins”) of the social network [facebook.com](http://www.facebook.com/), which is operated by Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, Dublin 2, Ireland (“Facebook”). The plugins can represent interaction elements or content (e.g. videos, graphics or text contributions) and can be recognized by one of the Facebook logos (white “f” on blue tile, the term “Like” or a “thumbs up” sign ) or are marked with the addition “Facebook Social Plugin”. The list and appearance of Facebook Social Plugins can be viewed here: <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>.

Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active).

When a user invokes a feature of this online offering that includes such a plugin, their device establishes a direct connection to the Facebook servers. The content of the plugin is transmitted by Facebook directly to the device of the user and incorporated by him into the online offer. In the process, user profiles can be created from the processed data. We therefore have no influence on the amount of data that Facebook collects with the help of this plugin and therefore inform the users according to our knowledge.

By integrating the plugins, Facebook receives the information that a user has accessed the corresponding page of the online offer. If the user is logged in to Facebook, Facebook can assign the visit to his Facebook account. If users interact with the plugins, for example press the “Like” button or leave a comment, the information is transmitted from your device directly to Facebook and stored there. If a user is not a member of Facebook, there is still the possibility that Facebook will find out and save their IP address. According to Facebook, only an anonymous IP address is stored in Germany.

The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook, as well as the related rights and setting options for protecting the privacy of users, can be found in Facebook’s privacy policy: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/> .

If a user is a Facebook member and does not want Facebook to collect data about him via this online offer and link it to his member data stored on Facebook, he must log out of Facebook and delete his cookies before using our online offer. Other settings and inconsistencies regarding the use of data for advertising purposes are possible within the Facebook profile settings: <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads> or via the US-American site <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or the EU page <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>. The settings are platform independent, i.e. they are adopted for all devices, such as desktop computers or mobile devices.

Within our online offer, features and content of the Twitter service offered by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA, may be incorporated. For this, e.g. content such as images, videos, or text and buttons that users use to promote their content, subscribe to content creators, or subscribe to our posts. If the users are members of the platform Twitter, Twitter can call the above-mentioned assign contents and functions to the profiles of the users there. Twitter is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation. ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active) ). Privacy Policy: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy> , Opt-Out: <https://twitter.com/personalization>.

## All possible contradictions (opt-out) at a glance:
